Finding Aid for the Alberto Sánchez de Iriarte Collection [Spanish Civil War]
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series IV: Magazine Fragments, Latin America, 1907-1942
  - E-Z
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), pgs. 257-260,Colombia, December 13, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), pgs. 1167-1162, Colombia, March 14, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), Colombia, April 18, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), pgs. 913-916 and 925-926, Colombia, August 29, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), pgs. 5-6, Colombia, April 29, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), pgs. 795-800, Colombia, March 9, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - El Gráfico (The Graphic), pgs. 977-986, Colombia, August 27, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - El suplemento (The Supplement), pgs. 59-62, Argentina, Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - El tiempo Ilustrado (Time Illustrated), pgs. 255-258, Mexico, April 12, 1907 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - El tiempo Ilustrado (Time Illustrated), pgs. 509-510, Mexico, August 1, 1909 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Haring C.H., “La Real Hacienda en los primeros tiempos del Coloniaje Español” Inter-América, (“The Royal Hacienda in the early years of Spanish Colonization,” Inter-America magazine), pgs. 220-232, New York, November 1918 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Historia de Diego Rivera (History of Diego Rivera), Mexico, Undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Kémmerer, E.W., Una proposición de Unidad Monetaria Panamericana, Inter-América (A proposition for Pan-American Monetary Unit, Inter-America), pgs. 41-49, New York, May 1917 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - La Estirpe, Brazil, July 15, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - La Estirpe, Brazil, August 1, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - La Nueva Democracia (The New Democracy), Magazine Clippings, New York, 1921-1925 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - La Nueva Democracia (The New Democracy), pgs. 15-16, New York, August 1920 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - La Nueva Democracia (The New Democracy), pgs. 21-22, New York, August 1924 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - La Nueva Democracia (The New Democracy), pgs. 25-26, New York, May 1925 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - La Nueva Democracia (The New Democracy), pgs. 13-16, New York, August 1926 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - La Nueva Democracia (The New Democracy), pgs. 15-28, New York, August 1935 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Paris-Sud Ameriqué (Paris-South America) pgs. 13-16, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Patria (Homeland), pgs. 5-6 and 13-16, Colombia, October 4, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Patria (Homeland), pgs. 5-6 and 11-14, Colombia, October 18, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Patria (Homeland), pgs. 5-6 and 19-22, Colombia, October 23, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Revista Colombiana (Colombiana Magazine) pgs. 47-52, April 15, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Revista de Instrucción Pública de Colombia (Public Instruction Magazine of Colombia), pgs. 351-360, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Revista de Industrias (Magazine of Industries), pgs. 151-152, Colombia, September 1924 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Revista de Industrias (Magazine of Industries), pgs. 19-22, Colombia, June 1926 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Revista de Revistas (Magazine of Magazines), Mexico, September 9, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Revista de Revistas (Magazine of Magazines), Colombia, April 20, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Revista de Revistas (Magazine of Magazines), Colombia, August 17, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Revista Diplomática y Consular Argentina (Diplomatic and Consular Magazine of Argentina), November 1915 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Rodríguez Piñeres, Eduardo, “Caudillismo y Civilismo”, Revista Contemporánea (Caudillismo and Antimilitarism, Contemporary Magazine), pgs. 150-159, Colombia, February 17, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Revista de la Instrucción Pública (Magazine of Public Instruction), pgs. 493-502, Cuba, December 1918 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Revista de la Sociedad Juridico-Literaria de Quito (Magazine of the Legal-Literary Society of Quito), pgs. 107-118, Ecuador, August 1916 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Revista de la Universidad (University Magazine), pgs. 117-124, Latin America, Undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Senderos (Trails), pgs. 367-374, Colombia, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Social, Cuba, April 1924 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Social, Cuba, September 1927 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Social, Cuba, February 1929 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Social, Cuba, November 1929 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Townsend Little, Flora, “La Jardinería Considerada como una de las Bellas Artes,” Inter-América (Gardening Considered as one of the Fine Arts ) Inter-America), pgs. 223-228, November 1923 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Tricolor, Las tallas Españolas en madera ( Spanish Wood Carvings), Mimeographed, Mexico, November 1922 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Unión Ibero-Americana (Ibero-American Union) pgs. 5-10, Uruguay, 1917 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Un Aerolito Colosal (A Colosal Meteorite) Billiken magazine clipping, Venezuela, April 5, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, September 22, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, October 6, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, October 13, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, October 7, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, March 2, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, March 9, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, April 6, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Universidad (University), Colombia, April 20, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Universida d (University), Colombia, August 17, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Universidad (University), Mexico, November 1936 (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - Vía Libre (Free Way) pgs. 11-14, Bolivia, August 1942 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Zimmern, Alfred E., Nacionalismo e Internacionalismo, Inter-Americana (Nationalisim and Internationalism), pgs. 229-236, New York City, November 1923 (Box 12, Folder 59)
- Series V: Spanish Civil War Publications, 1935-1939
  - A-W
    - Among Friends, Magazine ,Volume 1, Number 1, New York City, Winter 1938 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Among Friends, Magazine, Volume 1, Number 2, New York City, Spring 1938 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Batallón de Infantería No. 47, “Octubre”, Valsameda, Boleta de Sanidad (Infantry Battalion No. 47 “October”, Valsameda, Health Report), March 3,1937 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Batallón de Infantería No. 47, “Octubre”, Hoja de Prendas (Infantry Battalion No. 47 “October”, Garment Sheet), 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Bombs over Barcelona, New York City, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Class Struggle, Special Spanish Issue, Chicago IL, September 1937 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Edicions del Comissariat de Propaganda de la Generalitad de Calatunya, (Editions of the Propaganda Commissariat Generalitat of Catalonia) Broadsides, Undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Egas, Camilo, “Life in the Making: Robert Capa’s Photographs of Spain”, Program, New York City, February-March (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Estudios (Studies), Magazine, Year 15, Number 161, Spain, February 1937 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Estudios (Studies), Magazine, Year 15, Number 163, Spain, April 1937 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Estudios (Studies), Magazine, Year 15, Number 164, Spain, May 1937 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Facts and Figures on War and Fascism, Number 50, New York City, February 1,1937 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Facts and Figures on War and Fascism, Number 60, New York City, July 15,1937 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Committee for Spain, Medical Aid to Spain or China, Donation Slip, New York City, Undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Galicia Mártir, “Estampas por Castelao” (Galicia Martyr, Illustrations by Castelao) New York City, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - “In Memorian; Chicago Haymarket Martyrs”, Music Program, New York City, November 11,1937 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - International Review, Magazine, Volume 2, Number 5, New York, June 1937 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Industrial Workers of the World, “What’s What in Spain”, Broadside, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Johnson, Hewlette, “Durango 1937” Illustrated Book (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Lo que he Visto en Madrid (What I have seen in Madrid), Book, Spain, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Morrow, Felix, Revolution and Counter-Revolution in Spain, Book, New York City, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Morrow, Felix, The Civil War in Spain, Towards Socialism or Fascism? Book, New York City, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, “Christmas in Spain”, Bulletin, New York City, December 1937 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Oehler, Hugo, “Barricades in Barcelona, The First Revolt of the Proletariat against the People’s Front”, New York City, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Pitcairn, Frank, “Reporter in Spain”, Book, Moscow, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Program Bureau, Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign, “Pilot: A Manual of Directions”, New York City, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Reprisals in Spain, Evidence gathered from Newspaper Sources from March 31st to June 6, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Seven Years of the Spanish Republic, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Sinclair, Upton, No Pasarán! (They Shall not Pass), A Story of the Battle of Madrid, Book, California, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Soon the Snow will fall in Spain, Broadside, New York City, Undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Spain Today, Broadside, New York City, Undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Spanish Labor News, January 13, 1937, Number 9, New York City (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Strong, Anna Louise, “Spain in Arms 1937”, Book, New York City (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - The Lads of the International Brigade, Postcard, Undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - The Medical Bureau and North American Committee to aid Spanish Democracy, “Two Years of American Aid to Spain”, Magazine, New York City, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - The Spanish Revolution: Threatened by Enemies from Within, Broadside, Undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - The Vanguard Group, “Spanish Revolution”, Broadside, New York City, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - United Front in Defence of Workers’ Rights in Loyalist Spain, “Behind the Lines in Spain: Capitalist Democracy or Social Revolution…Which way to defeat Franco”, Bulletin, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - United Libertarian Organizations, “Grand Country Festival for Benefit of: Libertarian Press-CNT-FAI”, Propaganda, New York, Undated (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - United Youth Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, “Spain: the Spanish War in Pictures: Latest photos of Spain's Fight for Democracy”, Magazine, New York City, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - What’s What in Spain, Broadside, Undated (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Wolfe, Bertram D, The Civil War in Spain, Book, New York City, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 42)
- Series V: Spanish Civil War Publications, 1935-1939
  - (Legal Size) B-S
    - Boletín de Información (Information Bulletin, No. 44, Spain), July 16, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Boletín de Información (Information Bulletin, No. 58, Spain), February 1938 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Boletín de Información (Information Bulletin, No. 61, Spain), March 5, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Boletín de Información (Information Bulletin, No. 63, Spain), March 19, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - CNT, FAI, “19 Julio 1936, España”, (July 19, 1936, Spain) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Frente Popular, “Boletín de las Organizaciones Anfifascistas Hispanas de los EE.UU. de Norte América”, (Popular Front, Bulletin for the Hispanic Antifascist Organizations of the USA, New York City, Extraordinary Issue), 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - González, Leopoldo, “¡No Pasarán! They Shall Not Pass!”, Music Scores, New York City, Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Jordan, Henry and Mark Severn, “Spain Marches”, (Music Scores, New York City, Undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Madrid (The Destruction of Madrid, Photographic Book), Spain, February 1937 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Peters, Jack, “The Song of the Abraham Lincoln Battalion”, Music Scores, New York City, Undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Spain Illustrated, Magazine, No. 2, England, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 4, New York City, January 27, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 5, New York City, February 3, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 6, New York City, February 10 1938 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 7, New York City, February 17, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 8, New York City, February 24, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 9, New York City, March 3, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 10, New York City, March 10, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 11, New York City, March 17, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 13, New York City, March 31, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 28, Chicago, October 14, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 29, Chicago, November 4, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 30, Chicago, November 14, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 31, Chicago, November 21, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 32, Chicago, December 9, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 1, Number 33, Chicago, December 27, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, Volume 2, Number 34, Chicago, January 9, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Series VI: Spanish Civil War Pamphlets, 1935-1939
  - A-L
    - A Catholic Looks at Spain (Published by the Labor Publications Department), London, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - A Declaration by the Basque Nationalist Catholic Youth on the Spanish War, (Published by the Press Dept. of the Spanish Embassy in London), 1936 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - American Democracy Vs. The Spanish Hierarchy (Published by the Spanish Information Bureau), New York City, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Ben Leider, American Hero (Published by the Ben Leider Memorial Fund), New York City, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Browder Earl, “Lenin and Spain” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, February 1937 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Browder Earl and Lawrence, Bill, “Next Steps to Win the War in Spain” (Published by The Workers Library Publishers), New York City, January 1938 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Brown, H. Runham, “A Challenge to Pacifism” (Published by the Enfield Middlesex War Resisters League), England, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Cadden Joseph,” Spain 1936” (Published by the International Youth Commission), New York City (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Catholics and the Civil War in Spain (Published by Three Arrows Press), New York City, January 1937 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Children Colonies (Published by The Spanish Republic National Council for Evacuated Children), Paris, November 1937 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Children in Concentration Camps (Published by the Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City, Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Christ or Franco? An Answer to the Collective Letter which the Spanish Episcopate issued to the Bishops of the World (Published by the Friends of Spain), London, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Dallet Joe, “Letters from Spain” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Delapreé, Louis, “The Martyrdom of Madrid”, Madrid, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Dimitroff, G., “Spain and the People’s Front” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, February 1937 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Dimitroff, Georgi, “Spain’s Year of the War” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, August 1937 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Dr. Walter B. Cannon: Address Delivered April 18, 1937 (Published by the American Buro to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Ercoli. M., “The Spanish Revolution” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, December 1936 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Famine Faces a Million in Spain (Published by the National Joint Committee for Spanish Relief), London, October 1937 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Fischer, Louis, “The War in Spain” (Published by the Nation), New York City, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Freemasons and Spain, Struggle of Masonic Liberalism Against Reactionism in Spain (Published by the Medical Bureau and North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - From a Hospital in Spain American Nurses Write (Published by the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Gannes, Harry, “How the Soviet Union Helps Spain” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, November 1936 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Gannes, Harry, “Soviets in Spain, The October Armed Uprising Against Fascism”(Published by the Workers Library Publishers, New York City, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Herring Hubert C., “Spain, Battleground for Democracy” (Published by Social Action), New York City, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - How Mussolini Provoked the Civil War (Published by United Editorial Ltd.) London, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Intellectuals and the Spanish Military Rebellion (Published by The Press Department of the Spanish Embassy in London), 1938 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - LAMBDA, “The Truth about Barcelona Events” (Published by Workers Age Publishers), New York City, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Langdon-Davies, John, “ The Spanish Church and Politics” (Published by The American Friends of Spanish Democracy), New York City, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Le Jardins de Brihuega (The Gardens of Brihuega), Published by Protection du Tresor Artistique National, Valencia, Spain, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 30)
- Series VI: Spanish Civil War Pamphlets, 1935-1939
  - M-W
    - Mediterranean, (Published by the Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City, Undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Madrid, The Military Atrocities of the Rebels, A Record of Massacre, Murder, Mutilation (Published by the Labor Party), London, January 1937 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Marinello, Juan, “Cultura en la España Republicana” (Culture in the Republican Spain, Published by the Spanish Information Bureau), New York City, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Marty, André, “Heroic Spain” (Published by the Workers Library Publishers), New York City, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Mckelvy White, David and Hawthorne, James, “From These Honored Dead…” (Published by the Friends of the Lincoln Brigade), New York City, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - North, Joseph, “Men in the Ranks, The Story of 12 Americans in Spain” (Published by the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade), New York City, March 1939 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Oliver, Edward H., “Sixth Anniversary of the Spanish Republic in Barcelona”(Published by the Revolutionary Workers League U.S.), Chicago, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Ornitz Lou, “Captured by Franco” (Published by the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Batallion), New York City, May 1939 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Pérez, Manuel, “Cuatro Meses de Barbarie, Mallorca Bajo el Terror Fascista” (Four Months of Barbarism, Mallorca Under Fascist Terror, Published by CNT-AIT), January 1937 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Rebel Opposition to Efforts for the Humanisation of the Civil War in Spain (Published by the Press Department of the Spanish Embassy in London), 1937 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Report on the visit by an All Party Group Members of Parliament to Spain (Published by the Press Department of the Embassy of Spain in London, August 27, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Robert, Pierre, “Spain Calling! Their Fight is our Fight” (Published by the International Publishing Company), London, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Rocker, Rudolf, “The Tragedy of Spain” (Published by Freie Arbieter Stimme), New York City, October 1937 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Rocker, Rudolf, “The Truth About Spain” (Published by Freie Arbieter Stimme), New York City, Undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Roure-Torent, J., ” The Organization of the Spanish Army”(Published by Association Hispanophile de France), Paris, April 1937 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Souchy, Augustin, “The Tragic Week in May” (Published by CNT-FAI),Barcelona, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Spain (Published by the American Friends of Spanish Democracy), New York City, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Spain 1938, Report of Trade Union and Labor Party Members Delegation to Spain February 1938 (Published by the International Brigade and Dependents Aid Committee), London (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Spain’s Democracy Talks to America (Published by the American League Against War and Fascism), New York City, October 1936 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - The Crime of Francisco Franco (Published by The North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City, Undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - The Crime of Guernica (Published by The North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy), New York City, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - The Cultural Work of Liberal Governments in the Generalitat of Catalonia (Published by: Progaganda Comissariat Generalitat of Catalonia), Spain, Undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - The Italo-German Aggression Against Spain, Three Speeches of Sr. Juan Negrin, President of the Council of Ministries of Spain, Geneva, September 1937 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - The Story of the Abraham Lincoln Battalion (Published by the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Battalion), New York City, Undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - The Struggle in Spain (Published by Fortune), New York City, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - The Truth about the Moscow Frame-up Trials (Published by the Revolutionary Workers League U.S.), Chicago 1937 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Unity for Spain: Correspondence between the Communist International and the Labor Socialist International, June-July 1937 (Published by the Workers Library Publishers) New York City, August 1937 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Verbatim Report of the Negotiations between the Second and Third Internationals on the Question of Supporting The Heroic Struggle of the Spanish Workers, London 1935 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - WPA Teachers in Spain (Published by the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade), New York City, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous, Spain
  - Arts, Music, Politics, Tourism and Other, 1931-1934
    - Art Catalogs
      - Asociación de Artistas de la Coruña, Exposición M. Colmeiro (Artists Association of The Coruña, M. Colmeiro Exhibition), Catalog, September 1934 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Cerámicas Plá-De la Herrería (Fine Arts Circle, Plá de la Herrería Ceramics Exhibition), Catalog, Madrid, November 1931 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Madelein Leroux (Fine Arts Circle, Madeleine Leroux), Catalog, May 1932 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición del Pintor Italiano Alve Valdemi (Fine Arts Circle, Exhibition of the Italian Painter Alve Valdemi), Catalog, May 1932 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Círculo de Bellas Artes, Exposición de Josefina Plá y Julián de la Herrería (Fine Arts Circle, Josefina Plá and Julián de la Herrería Exhibition) Invitation, November-December 1932 (Box 17, Folder 5)